<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Alex Davalos</title>
    <link>https://alexdavalos.com/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Alex Davalos</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2019 15:17:50 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://alexdavalos.com/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Todo List</title>
      <link>https://alexdavalos.com/projects/project-todolist/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2019 15:17:50 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexdavalos.com/projects/project-todolist/</guid>
      <description>View Source Application that allows users to add tasks to a todo list. User is able to add and remove tasks in the list. Added hovering feature to make it more clear to user which task their cursor is on.
Applied techniques learned from FreeCodeCamp&#39;s Learn React JS series - React fundamentals, React state, JSX, and css styling. This project helped me gain a better understanding of React.js fundamentals.
Skills Acquired:  React.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recipe Search App</title>
      <link>https://alexdavalos.com/projects/project-recipeapp/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 15:17:50 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexdavalos.com/projects/project-recipeapp/</guid>
      <description>View Source Application that allows user to look up recipes based off of a key ingredient. The application is written in React and the recipe search API from edamam.com. There are more than one million search results for this API!
Skills Acquired:  React API Javascript Async, Await UseEffect method  More projects will be added soon! </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Javascript Task List</title>
      <link>https://alexdavalos.com/projects/project-tasklist/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 15:17:50 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexdavalos.com/projects/project-tasklist/</guid>
      <description>Demo View Source Project from Traversy Media&#39;s Javascript Udemy course. Task list application that allows adding, removing, and filtering tasks. Tasks are stored in local storage. Page is styled with Materialize CSS.
Skills Acquired:  Javascript HTML5 Materialize DOM Manipulation Local Storage  More projects will be added soon! </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Calculator</title>
      <link>https://alexdavalos.com/projects/project-calc/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 15:17:50 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexdavalos.com/projects/project-calc/</guid>
      <description>Demo View Source Application modeled after the Google calculator. Applied techniques learned from JavaScript Crash Course - vanilla js, structuring app, and dom manipulation. This project helped me gain a better understanding of JavaScript fundamentals.
Skills Acquired:  Javascript HTML5 CSS3 ES6  More projects will be added soon! </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Netflix Page</title>
      <link>https://alexdavalos.com/projects/project-netflix/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 15:17:50 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexdavalos.com/projects/project-netflix/</guid>
      <description>Demo View Source Replicated a version of Netflix&#39;s webpage based off of project from Traversy Media&#39;s Udemy course.
Projects goal was to master the use of CSS including the concepts of Flexbox and Grid. Javascript was used to allow for content to be displayed on different tabs of the webpage. Page was designed to be responsive in case user viewed on a smaller screen such as a mobile device. Used the icon toolkit &amp;ldquo;Font Awesome&amp;rdquo; for icons.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>